A fairytale like no other.
Penelope is a fantasy, comedy, romance film directed by Mark Palansky.
Forlorn heiress Penelope Wilhern is cursed, and the only way out
is to fall in love with someone of suitable stock.
But how can she find her soulmate when she's sequestered inside her
family's estate with only her parents to keep her company?
This untraditional fairy tale is about a girl who bucks
convention to create her own happy ending.
Penelope Wilhern, played by Christina Ricci.
Johnny/Max, played by James McAvoy.
Jessica Wilhern, played by Catherine O'Hara.
Lemon, played by Peter Dinklage.
Franklin Wilhern, played by Richard E. Grant.
Annie, played by Reese Witherspoon.
Penelope is a 2006 fantasy romantic comedy film directed by Mark Palansky and starring
Christina Ricci, James McAvoy, Catherine O'Hara, Peter Dinklage, Richard E.
Grant, and Reese Witherspoon (who also produced the film).
The film tells the story of a young heiress named Penelope Wilhern, who had been born with the snout of a pig due to a curse that was placed on
her family by a vengeful witch, believing the only way to break the curse was to find another blue blood who truly loved her.
The film explores themes of marriage proposal,
isolation, pig, fairy tale, yellow press.
The tone is lighthearted and emotional.